This is the RP Centre. If you want to get a basic
surgery done or any eye-related
treatment done, then you will have to come here.
This is the entire line. After the appointment,
you will have to come here to get the card made
and stand in the line. You
can see that at 9:00 am on Sunday, there is so much
rush here.
First, take an online appointment, then I will leave from here.
After getting the card made, here
I am waiting for the OPD. First,
as I told you, you have to take an online
appointment and after that,
if you come here for the first time, then
you will have to get the card made first. If
you come for the second time, then the doctor will
write on it that you have to come
now and at what time you have to come. By doing this,
then you do not need to take an appointment again
online. So, let's
end today. The next
date I have got for getting a test done is
30th August. So, I will
come on 30th August. Next time, then I
will share with you what is the further procedure
for the surgery. After one month, that means 30th.
I had an appointment in August, you
can see how much rush there is, so there is
no such tension here right now because my
number is already booked, meaning once you book your
number, you don't need to book it again, let's go
inside now before someone
stops me, I don't want to get my heart done today, like the
first time I got it done,
my number is 102, let's see, the
room number is written now, its directions are made,
you can see,
as I told you, today
was my second visit here, so today
I had two procedures done, one for
dilute and one for fungus, so I would
like to give you a tip that whenever you come here,
even for the second visit, that is, when you have to get dilute
or fungus done, then bring someone with you
because you will
not be able to see nearby, you will not be able to use the phone,
and right now I have come in the sun, so
even the distant vision is blurred, I have
come alone, I am managing a little, there is
not that much blur, so this is the problem I am facing right now,
and today I had two
procedures done.  Now I have a little
doubt, so they have
called me again after next 3 days, they are saying that the surgery will be done
but they have some doubts, so they
want to check me once more and then
see, and it may not be the case for you,
you can get the operation date directly on your second visit itself,
but they have
called me once more, right now with you,
then on the next visit there
is also a third rate and today also the same procedure is happening
which I told you in the clip
that the funds will be done once again and along with
that, I will
definitely tell you what else will happen today, but I did not tell
you about today's visit in the clip,
today I went in manually, there is
something refractive, when we do the face, then there are
two parts in our eye, white and black, so there was
something like a spot in the white part, so
for that, if there is a spot in your eye, then
first the spots will be corrected with basic,
after that there will be an operation for your glasses, that is, the
spot will be corrected with laser first,
after that there will be a
separate laser for your glasses, so in a way there will be two
surgeries.  It will happen but today when the check was done again, they found my
support
but they did a
recheck of mine, in a way, they did not find my support,
friend, the
next video was called, in
a way, in PMT, DMT, it happens
that when will I get the final date, so
when I go to PMT, I will
tell you what they did,
after that, the date is less,
what about next, today is my fourth rate here
and the time given was 8:00, now it might be
8:15 and see how
much rush there is here, it is just to get the card made, so let's go
inside today,
pigmentation is some process,
what is pigmentation, I mean,
in short, I am going to get the
date today, when will my list surgery take place, let's
see what happens,
friend, today as I told you in the morning,
I had gone there and today is 6th September
and today was my fourth visit to AIIMS in a way
and today I had my PMT,
this is what happens in PMT that they ask you first,
like I  When I went, they called me and
asked me why I wanted to get the L-six surgery done.
I told them that I want it done
because I have been using specs for a long time
and now when I
shoot blogs etc., I face
problem in that. I
cannot shoot with glasses on. You know, I do a
lot of adventure activities, so
I want to get it changed, that is why I want to get the
surgery done. So I told them this and gave it to
them. After that they sent me back. Then they once again said that after an hour they checked my number. They checked my number to see if my number is fluctuating. It could be that 10 days ago I had a different number and now it is different. They found it similar in that too. Then they made
us wait for two-three hours. Then after that they
called us 12-15 members together and after that
they said that all of you are
eligible for the surgery. They
gave us two options, like 10-15 people and they
called everyone together because  If that
doctor had called us van by van, oh this bullet one, then
if he had called us van by van, then it would have been a
waste of time, so he called 10-15 people together
and told them that brother,
we have two options, SMILE
and LASIK, these are the two general options, and
their contour machine is still bad, and the
contour machine is so bad, that means they don't trust the controller, so
they give only these options
because I had asked some people before, they were
also saying that friend, they only
say LASIK for SMILE, so it was the same for me, they
said LASIK and SMILE, so
first they
told me the difference between LASIK and SMILE, what is the difference, I will
tell you that in LASIK, a
flap is cut
from the cornea and in SMILE, they
cut the flapping and do the
entire surgery from the side with laser,
this is the only difference and in LASIK, a little
more care has to be taken and
in basic, you have to do it for 15 days.
Pouring water, dust need to be done, then
you will have to do the same in Ismail for 10 days, but the
thing is the price is Rs.
52,000 in AIIMS and its price is
approx. 22,000, so there is a
difference of almost Rs. 30,000, so as we have so many
10-15 members, so out of these,
he said that some of them are eligible for both
and some are eligible for the basic and some are
eligible only for Smile, so in my case,
my
number is 4:30 on the left and approximately my
four-point mark is on the right, something like that,
meaning it is not in both but between four and
five, my number of both the IS is
and the marks of both are not different,
so in my case, they told me
that you are eligible for both,
but I did not have the budget, because if
I am running around so much in it, then
obviously I will not have the budget, otherwise
I  I could have got it done anywhere else, cheaper,
you mean, and I could have got it done there, I could have got it done
in any private hospital if
I had the budget, so I got the same LASIK done
because they have a
similar procedure and the after
surgery will be visible in both, you
just have to take a little more care,
but there is a price difference, so
obviously it will be done, there is no problem, so that is why
I got the LASIK done
and as of now, I have got the
date of 16th September for the surgery, so
before that they told me that
you will have to deposit the fee at least two days in advance, so
I should deposit it today itself,
because I had asked if it will be done today, so
they said yes, you can do it today also, then what would have happened, friend,
I would have had to go again two days in advance to
deposit it, so
I had gone today only, so as soon as
you go for PMT at the time, if you are coming
from far away, then I had gone from a very far,
so I got it done at the same time, that is, I got it done
today itself, so if you wait for
5 minutes, then you wait for two days  You can do it earlier as well, it is
your choice, so this was it. Now I have
surgery on the 16th. Initially, I thought that I will
make a complete post-surgery block all at once and show you all the
procedures involved, but then I thought that friend, you should not use the
surgery right now, I will
shoot a blog after approximately 15 days because
in between I will not be able to use the computer, mobile etc. much,
then editing etc. will also not be
possible, so then I thought that
I should tell you right now what the
procedure is, what are the
steps one by one, you know that,
whenever I say, I covered it in the blog, yes, I will also
tell you why I did not shoot there, because friend, I was not
going in such a way that if I shoot, someone will have an
objection or the doctor will get angry and say,
my friend, why are you shooting this or that here, then ultimately I will
also have to undergo surgery, so that is why I was
not taking any risk,
so I thought that I will tell you,
but there is internal inside, that is, I will
not shoot anything, that is why I did not shoot there.  I did
not do it and once when I was about to do it, he refused saying
that shooting is not allowed, so
I did not do it inside. That's it.
Now my surgery is on 16th. If
you have any question, you can ask me
in the comment section of this video.
If I am
not able to reply, then in the next video I will
put my experience, that is, how is my vision feeling
after the surgery, is it
all clear or whatever, and whatever
procedure is there, whatever care is required after the surgery,
I will
put a video for all of that on approximately 1st October. So
in that video I will cover all your points.
Now is the best time to get the
surgery done because what happens, Sir,
as you have started the procedure, it will take
you approximately 25 to 3 months. So
what happens during winter time, it will
not get into the eyes, so it is best to have
less tension about bathing, even if you do not take bath for two-three days, there will be no
problem
in the eyes.  Water should not be lost at the time of surgery,
so you should start the procedure right now so that
your number for surgery comes up in two months, that is after
Diwali,
and you can get the surgery done.
They have given me one drop by one, you should
not follow it because all that happens
according to this, so I thought that I should
put one drop for 15 days, then two
more drops have been written which you have to put three days before the surgery, so that is like that
and the rest,
you must have the link of all the surgeries on your screen,
see this photo, you should stop and
see, then you will go by the rest of the rates
and sir,
what are the prices of this that happens there, etc. That is all
for today, I will meet you
in the next blog after the specs, that is, what will be the specs
that I am shooting, after this, the blog that will be there, I
hope because
I have also deposited the fees, now the surgery is to be done on the
16th, I am waiting for that and
after that I will meet you next time, I will meet
you sometime next month and
will share my surgery experience with you.  Thank
you
[music]